Jane?
- Good morning, Lisbon.
- Hi.
- What happened to your wrist?
- Ah, it's nothing. I tripped.
What are you doing?
We're close. Very close.
- How close is very close?
- Oh... about, uh, this close.
- Tell me.
- No. First I need to sleep.
- No, first you need to tell.
- I haven't slept in a week, Lisbon.
- I am beat.
- Jane...
I need to sleep.
Come on. You're killing me!
Just gonna take
a little rest here.
Just a little one.
Just a little sleep.
Jane.
Okay.
Thank you.
Jane?
Wake up.
Jane. Come on.
Where... what is it?
We got a call on a homicide
in a motel in east Sac.
Yeah?
The first responders say
it looks like Red John.
So what do you think?
Is this bogus, or actual Red John?
I've worked Red John's murder scenes
since he began. It's totally bogus.
Ah, that's a shame.
I always wanted to work
one of the famous killers.
Eh, he's been laying low for years
working through friends and proxies.
- He killed just recently, didn't he?
- Eh, that was an internal issue.
Lorelei Martins was one
of his own people. It doesn't count.
Could you guys give us a moment?
Hey, Lisbon.
Jane.
- Uh, this is my colleague Val Ziskin.
- Hi.
You're sure this wasn't Red John
are you, Mr. Partridge?
- Uh... yeah.
- You 100% sure?
No, I mean, I'm surmising.
You're the expert.
Well, you heard
what she said.
- Excuse me?
- Out.
- I have a job to do.
You can come back later.
Do you think he's right?
- This is Red John.
- How can you tell?
Because when it's him,
I can feel it.
She looks familiar.
What do we know about her?
She's a Jane Doe.
She's been at the motel for five days.
Paid cash. Checked in
under a false name.
As you can see,
she had a baby with her
around 6 months old,
that went missing.
Not Red John's M.O. at all.
True. He must have had an accomplice
who needed a baby for some reason.
Or it's not Red John.
No, it's him.
Uh, yes, hi. Uh...
Where are your offices located?
Thank you.
Child Protective Services.
Carson Springs.
Well, you say that like it's bad.
Yeah, well, when I was a kid,
I spent a little time there.
You think it's connected?
Probably not.
It's strange. Right at this precise
moment when you get close
Red John reappears
and murders somebody.
It's got to be a coincidence, right?
I hope so.
- Are you gonna make me beg?
- For what?
Come on, stop it!
How close are you exactly?
Assuming Lorelei's
telling the truth
Red John is one of 1,357 men
who I've shaken hands with
since my wife and daughter
were killed.
I've whittled that list down
to only those men
who could have possibly been
at all Red John murder sites.
And how many is that?
I have a list of seven names.
That's great. That's amazing.
Tell me the names.
I don't think that
that's a good idea.
- What? Are you kidding?
- Please watch the road.
Yes, sir, I'm the night clerk.
I was here all night
listening to the radio.
She was being murdered
50 feet away from me.
I couldn't hear a thing.
It's creepy.
Any unusual visitors that night,
or earlier in the day?
No. Yes! Well, not yesterday,
but the day before
a guy walks in,
he asks me if we have a woman
with a baby staying, so I say no
because he looked like trouble.
And what does trouble look like?
A big white dude.
Um, brown hair, beard.
Um, foreign accent.
I think Irish, it was.
But when I tell the poor lady
about him
she says to me, "thank you,"
like I did the right thing.
Could you identify him
if you saw him again?
Oh, yeah, absolutely.
We need to talk to the maid
that found the body... Sandra Guzman?
Oh, she went home.
She's not here.
Didn't the local police tell her
she had to stay to talk with us?
Yeah, she was really upset,
you know... shivering.
She had blood all over her.
She tells me
that she's freaking out
and she couldn't talk to nobody,
and she had to go home.
She couldn't talk why?
I don't know.
She's a strange one, you know?
She's one of those with black
hair, rings, goth-like, you know?
- You have an address for Sandra?
- Yeah. Uh, in the office, I think.
Yes. Um... I could show you.
Well, why won't you tell me?
If I tell you why I won't tell you
then you'll get mad at me.
I'm already mad at you.
Just tell me.
No, you're not mad, you're just vexed.
There is a difference.
Hello.
We're with the CBI.
We need to talk to whoever's in charge.
Yes, ma'am.
Miss Gottlieb, we have
an unidentified murder victim.
And your phone number
was written on her wall.
I'm gonna show you a photo of the woman
and see if you recognize her.
- She's dead, so it may be disturbing.
- Oh, my gosh. Okay.
You know her.
It's Eileen.
Eileen Turner.
What about Caitlyn?
Is she... is Caitlyn safe?
- Is that her baby?
- Yes. Where is she?
We don't know.
Whoever killed Eileen
may have taken her.
- Oh, my God!
- Do you have any...
the man you want is Roddy Turner
Eileen's husband.
Do you think he's responsible?
He was abusive towards her.
Violent.
She left him a week ago.
We were helping her get
a restraining order against him.
Um... here we are.
His address is 1204 Stoney Ridge.
- Wait.
- That's about...
I know where that is.
Uh, thank you.
Thank you for your help.
- We may be back.
- Of course. Anything I can do.
Jane?
Stoney Ridge is a traditional
carny layover.
In the winter, when we would
go to Carson Springs
it's where we'd stay...
Stoney Ridge.
I mean, it's practically
my hometown.
- Oh!
- Yeah. "Oh."
It must be a coincidence.
Or Red John is deliberately
bringing me home.
How would he even know
about this place?
Holy smokes! Patrick!
Hey, Pete! It's Patrick Jane!
Hey, Sam.
Patty, me boy!
It's good to see you!
- Yeah.
- What the hell are you doing here?
I'm sorry. We don't
have a formal I.D.
but we're pretty sure it's her.
We found her this morning
at the Torchlite Motel in Sacramento.
- Where's Caitlyn?
- She's missing.
- Missing?
- Oh, my God.
We and several other agencies
are doing everything we can to find her.
Now what's your connection
to Eileen?
She's married to my nephew
Roddy.
They've been living with us
for a while in the Airstream.
I don't recall a nephew.
My sister's boy. Came over
from Ireland five years ago.
He's a lead rigger. Puts up
the big wheels and the coasters.
- He's a good lad.
- Uh, where's Roddy now?
He's been out driving around
looking for Eileen and Caitlyn
ever since they went.
We need to talk to him.
Does he have a phone?
No.
Oh, come on, Pete.
It's me. We're...we're family.
I mean, how long have the Janes
and the Turners been traveling together?
A hundred years now, probably.
Roddy's got no phone.
Okay. So Eileen left
a week ago, yes?
- Yeah.
- Why?
We don't know.
They'd been having
a hard time financially.
And they're both Leos. That can cause
arguments but nothing serious.
Caityln's social worker had mentioned
abuse and violence.
In a pig's eye!
Social workers, eh?
Last month, Roddy and Eileen
had a bit of a go
and the cops came and
they made a big deal of nothing
and they called in child welfare.
It was a bunch of nonsense.
Eileen and Roddy love each other
and they're great parents.
What kind of car
was Roddy driving?
Gee, I... I don't know.
I think he borrowed it from a friend.
What's his friend's name?
- I can't remember. Do you remember?
- Nope.
Caitlyn's life is at stake here.
We need your cooperation.
Roddy didn't kill Eileen,
so he hasn't got Caitlyn.
- You had another name in mind.
- No name in mind.
All right. Have it your way.
Pete's calling Roddy right now.
If Roddy's innocent,
which I think he is
he'll feel compelled
to go to the crime scene.
If he's innocent,
why not contact the police?
Oh, 'cause no man in that family's
gonna willingly contact the police.
Hey.
- "Hi, boss."
- Where are you?
We're looking for Sandra Guzman
the motel maid that found the body.
- She's playing hard to get.
- "Oh, take a break from that."
Get to the motel as quick
as you can and stake it out.
We think the victim's husband
might be headed over there.
Tell him he's innocent.
We just need to talk to him.
Uh, we don't know if he's involved
but bring him in. Be careful.
Will do.
What makes you so sure
Roddy Turner's innocent?
Well, I'm not sure about
anything right now.
Except that you won't tell me
the names on the list.
You're sure of that.
Yeah, well, I should tell you
why I'm not gonna tell you.
Some of the names
are people that you know
and you'll start acting
differently around them
- and you may tip them off.
- What?! No, I won't!
Well... Yes, you will.
You can't help yourself.
I mean, no offense
but you have no dishonesty in you.
I have dishonesty in me.
I can put on a front.
This is you putting on a front...
- No, it's not. I can keep secrets.
- Oh, okay.
I have secrets from you.
- Secrets you cannot imagine.
- Right. Well, of course.
How about I tell you
three things about you
that you think are secrets
from me that I actually know?
Then will you be convinced?
- Sure. Go ahead.
- Okay.
You know what? Wait.
Don't bother.
I won't stoop to playing
your silly games.
Wise call.
- Are these people I know well?
- Very well.
- J.J. LaRoche?
- No.
- Ardiles?
- Interesting guess. No.
Would you tell me if I guess right?
- Nope.
- You're killing me.
- So what's new with you?
- Nothing.
Same old, same old, huh?
Yeah, me, too, pretty much.
- Except for one thing.
- Yeah, I know.
You know?
You know what?
You and Van Pelt
are having sex again.
Yeah. Yes.
I mean, I wouldn't call it that.
"Having sex." Kind of... clinical.
- You're not having sex?
- No. Uh... yes, we are, of course.
But it's more than that.
- We're in love.
- Yeah? No kidding. Congratulations.
How did you know? We were
keeping it on the way down low.
Good job.
Could I help you?
Hey! CBI! Stop!
Hey!
- Where is she?
- Roddy, stop that right now!
Put your hands on your head!
Do it now!
I was just doing my job,
and this maniac
comes in and attacks me!
I thought I was gonna die!
- You're alive. Be quiet.
- Where are they?
Sir, we understand your anger,
and we're sorry for your loss
but we want to talk quietly someplace.
You need to come back to our office.
When did she leave you?
Roddy, you need to talk to us.
If you didn't do this,
we need to know
so we can find the man
responsible.
And find your child.
- "You want to help us find Caitlyn, right?"
- "Let me go."
You assaulted a cop
and a CSI technician.
- You're not going anywhere.
- I need to find me daughter.
Please. Let me go.
- He didn't do it.
- Hold on. Uh, if he did do it
he did at as some sort of accomplice
to Red John, right?
True. But Red John always offers his friends
something that they don't have.
Why does Roddy need
Red John?
I mean, what's his motive?
Where's his child?
Good questions.
Still, I get the distinct feeling
that he's hiding something.
Me, too. Same thing Pete
and Samantha were hiding.
Someone else they suspect.
Which would suggest
a family dispute.
Yes, it does.
Who is Eileen's family?
Where's she from?
- Family name is Barlow.
- Barlow?
Yeah, she was born
in Modesto.
Her parents were Kevin
and Suzanne Barlow.
They were killed in a car accident
when she was 3 years old.
- She's Leelee Barlow.
- You knew her?
Well, after Eileen's parents
were killed...
she was raised
by her Uncle Sean.
He was very close with my father.
Yeah, well, they fell out over
a business deal became enemies.
But, uh, I haven't seen Eileen
or Sean for at least 30 years.
You think that Eileen's murderer is maybe
connected to this Sean Barlow?
Well, Pete thinks so. Otherwise
he would have told me who she was.
What else?
There was something about
remembering Eileen Barlow
that freaked you out...
what is it?
Oh, you're getting good, Lisbon.
Don't patronize me.
Just tell me. What's the deal?
You know how some certain
little random
childhood memories
stick with you forever?
You know, and oftentimes they're associated
with a piece of music or a song?
Sure. You know that song about
the cake being left out in the rain?
I always see my mother feeding pigeons.
I don't know why.
Whenever I think of
happy times in my childhood
I see a certain image.
It's... it's a fourth of July picnic.
"You know, I'm about 12 or so
and there's music playing."
"There's a... a young girl laughing"
as she's being lifted
into the air by her father.
Eileen Barlow.
Well, people called her
Leelee back then.
I don't think I ever
saw her again after that day.
She's just a memory
that made me smile.
And Red John killed her.
I... It's like he just reached into my head
and killed a happy memory.
How is it possible?
- How could he read your mind?
- I don't know.
- Hell of a trick, though, right?
- It's a coincidence. It must be.
Yeah. Yeah, it must be.
Uh, could you do me a favor?
Could wait in the car when I talk to Pete?
- Okay.
- It's not that he dislikes you.
It's just, you know, you're...
you're police.
- I understand.
- Thank you.
- What?
- You know what.
So you say.
Why didn't you tell me
Eileen was a Barlow?
You didn't ask me.
You think Sean Barlow
was behind her murder.
And you're as calm
as you are about Caitlyn
because you assume the Barlows
are gonna take good care of her.
Is that so?
And you're just waiting for me
and the cops to move on
then you and Roddy are gonna
take care of this yourselves.
No.
The only thing
I don't know is why.
Why would you think that Sean Barlow
would kill his own niece?
- It's your theory, not mine.
- No. It's yours.
And you're probably wrong.
This murder was done by Red John.
I mean, Sean Barlow
may have helped him...
But if he did, and you know he did
you better tell me why right now.
- Like I said...
- Don't you even try to lie to me.
Sean Barlow has always
hated Roddy.
He forbade Eileen to see him,
but she did anyhow.
- Why does he hate Roddy?
- The travel circuit
in Britain and Ireland
is a tough go.
And Roddy used to be
a little salty.
Used to be.
He's a calmer fellow now.
But he broke some faces
he should have left alone.
He was one step ahead of trouble
when my sister sent him over here to me.
Anyhow, some of the injured parties
were cousins to the Barlows
and Sean Barlow loves
to cultivate a grudge.
Grudge enough to murder
his own niece?
You don't know Sean Barlow.
He disowned Eileen,
called her a whore.
He demanded money from Roddy
for payment for lost Barlow property.
Roddy refused, of course
and Sean accused him of theft
and swore vengeance.
- Swore vengeance?
- In a manner of words, yeah.
And what's his connection to Red John?
It doesn't quite fit.
Sean Barlow is a sinister
piece of work.
He's mean and clever.
Hell, Patty...
For all I know, Sean Barlow
may be Red John.
Give me an address.
You know, you should
probably wait here.
Not a chance in hell.
Uh, he's old school like Pete.
He's not gonna want to talk to a cop.
We'll see.
I'm old school, too.
- Seriously.
- Seriously!
I didn't come here all the way
from Sacramento to wait outside.
Welcome, welcome.
You're very welcome.
I'm Marta.
How can I help you?
Relax, sister,
we're not chumps.
She's a cop,
and I'm in on the gag.
- What do you want?
- To talk to Sean Barlow.
There's no Sean Barlow here.
She's almost as bad
a liar as you are.
You tell Sean...
who isn't here...
that Patrick Jane is here,
and he'd like to talk to him. We'll wait.
Patrick Jane. It is you.
I didn't believe her!
Hello, Mr. Barlow.
Oh... Call me Sean,
my boy...Sean.
Well, I haven't seen you
since you were, what? 15?
You haven't changed a bit.
And you've brought
a policewoman with you.
Great pleasure to meet you,
young lady.
Come on upstairs
and let's catch up.
I've been following
your doings, Patrick.
- I know why you're here.
- Well, of course you do.
My grandfather came over from Ireland
with this one's great grandfather.
His father and I
were great friends.
He was a wicked man,
but I loved him.
A wicked man?
You're a spiritual person,
aren't you, Teresa?
- You believe in life after death?
- Yes.
Then you'll agree it's a sad thing
to be an unbeliever
- to have no faith.
- Yes.
And when faithless men
use the faith and belief of others
to steal from them with lies
like the Janes do.
That's sad and wicked.
I agree.
I don't do it anymore.
No. A lawman now.
It's atonement you're after, is it?
Well, the Janes never
pretended to have powers
especially with people
in the show
but, the Barlows always tried to pass
themselves off as "real" psychics.
Because we are.
Well, you said you knew
why we were here.
Yeah, it was on the news.
Eileen is dead, murdered.
- You don't seem so upset about it.
- She was already dead to me
when she left the family
for that scum.
I mourned her passing long ago.
I want the baby, though.
She'll be raised a Barlow.
Where were you the night
before last?
Oh, I was far away,
communing with the spirits.
Where were you?
Let me see.
Lying in bed,
thinking of Patrick.
You're a little in love
with him, eh?
But he's so secretive
and controlling.
That's hard, isn't it?
We're here because of Eileen.
It was that scum Roddy Turner
killed her, no doubt.
Well, Roddy and his Uncle
say it was you.
Words are cheap.
It was Roddy she was afraid of,
wasn't it?
It was him,
and God knows he'll pay.
Well, whoever killed Eileen and took Caitlyn
they had help from Red John
and you're more
the Red John type of man.
Red John. Any punk killer
who wants to fool with you
can paint a smiley face
on the wall.
- "Oh, it's Red John"
- it was Red John.
Red John has
your mind completely messed up.
You see him every place
you look.
You think you're getting closer,
but he is just playing with you.
- We'll see.
- Has it never occurred to you
to ask exactly how Red John
is always one step ahead of you?
How is it he seems
to read your mind?
- You tell me.
- Red John's got powers.
Real psychic powers
that you refuse to believe in.
Teresa will hear what I'm saying
but you've no faith
so you're deaf to the truth.
He's got powers.
That's why he'll always defeat you.
So I take it you have no alibi
for the night before last.
No. No, I don't.
- Thank you for your time, Mr. Barlow.
- Entirely my pleasure.
It's odd, isn't it
how the daughters of alcoholics
so often are the best
kind of women.
When you find the baby, bring her to me.
She'll be well looked after.
That's not the way it works.
Oh, does it not?
I'm sure we'll sort something out.
Think on what I said.
It's honest advice
from a friend.
Good seeing you, Sean.
Wow. That was intense.
You okay?
Oh, I'm fine. You okay?
He didn't spook you, did he?
Yeah. He didn't spook you?
Ah, he's a good showman.
I'll give him that.
I couldn't read him.
He might have killed Eileen,
or... he might be right.
Maybe he believes
that Roddy did do it.
Or... Maybe I've just fallen
for some punk playing a trick.
What if he's right?
What if Red John really
does have powers?
Please! And what if dolphins
were actually aliens
from another galaxy?
That would be kind of cool.
I'm serious. How did
Red John do what he did?
He read your mind.
It was a cool trick,
just like I said.
We're looking for this woman...
Sandra Guzman... have you seen her?
She just got on the bus.
CBI!
Hey, Sandra.
Why have you been running
from us, Sandra?
We just wanted to talk to you
about what you saw at the motel.
Did you see in that room?
That was the devil in there.
I don't want nothing to do with that.
I don't wanna talk about it.
"I just want to forget
I ever saw it."
- And how's that working out for you?
- Not so good.
I can't sleep.
Every time I close my eyes,
I see that poor woman.
So maybe you do need
to talk about it.
Tell me exactly what you saw
when you walked into the room.
I was...
I was pulling my cart in
so I didn't see the bed right away.
And I was thinking she moved out
because before, when I did the room
she had, like, stacks
of diapers and baby milk.
But it was all gone.
So I thought they left.
And then I turn around
looked at the bed,
and, oh, my God.
Her eyes were open,
looking right at me.
I fell down,
I was so scared.
The carpet was all wet
with her blood.
And when you arrived
for work that morning
did you notice any strangers?
Anybody acting weird?
- Anything out of the ordinary?
- Nothing.
- What happened to the baby?
- We don't know yet.
The motel maid... blameless.
But illuminating. We need
to go back to Carson Springs
but first, you need to let
Roddy Turner go.
Okay.
Thank you.
Okay, so we have
two prime suspects.
Roddy Turner... Eileen's husband...
and Sean Barlow... her uncle.
Both men are pointing at each
other as the guilty party.
We need your help to find out
which one is in fact the killer.
Uh, don't worry.
There'll be no danger.
Oh, I don't mind that.
What's the plan exactly?
We're gonna let both men know
that there is a baby...
a baby that resembles baby Caitlyn...
that has been left here with you.
Now we're assuming that
the killer has baby Caitlyn
or knows where she is,
so he will know
that the baby that's left here
with you is not her.
Oh, I see.
So only the innocent man
will show up to see
if the baby is Caitlyn.
Exactly. And the guilty man
simply won't show.
- Clever.
- If you're willing.
- Of course.
- Splendid.
Great.
A little girl has been left
at the CPS offices in Carson Springs.
I am trying to confirm I.D.
as Caitlyn Turner
and you're listed
as one of the contacts.
"Does Caitlyn have a small
birthmark on her left arm?"
Yes. Yes, she does.
- Yeah, hello?
- Hey, Sean.
Some lady here says
they found baby Caitlyn.
- Look...
- You know, I've been thinking.
- So have I.
- You first.
- I can't work like this...
- No, sorry, wrong. Me first.
Sean was right. I've been...
secretive and controlling, and...
I'm gonna tell you
the seven names on the list
but you need to promise me
you will not tell
another living soul... nobody.
Well, how can I put them
under surveillance
and investigate them if I can't tell
anybody at the CBI who they are?
You can't.
- But I don't have...
- Nobody. Especially the CBI.
Why?
Because one of the names
on the list is Gale Bertram.
- What?
- Your boss.
- No.
- Yes.
Oh, my God.
How am I gonna face him?
- Well...
- Who else?
- Roddy Turner.
- What?
Over there.
Aye. They said you have
my daughter here.
Mr. Turner?
- Where's Caitlyn?!
- Mr. Turner!
- What is this?
- I'm sorry. It was a false alarm.
- Caitlyn's not here.
- What?
It was a trick to flush out
Eileen's killer
who didn't come because he knows
that Caitlyn wouldn't be here.
This is interesting.
Well, what the hell
is this then?
Yes. Sorry.
Sorry for what?
Where's Caitlyn?
You know Roddy, don't you?
Good news is you're both here,
which means neither of you killed Eileen.
That's off to a reasonably
good start.
Gentlemen, please don't
even think about it.
Eileen would want you two
to be making peace.
Like hell she would.
- You had better have a damn good...
- Hold that thought.
Excuse me.
Uh, yes, Van Pelt?
You'd better talk very quickly.
My phone is about to run out of juice
and I'm under a little pressure here.
Hi. I'm calling like you said.
And good luck. I hope it works.
What? Where?
Uh, are you sure?
Yeah.
Yeah, okay. We'll be right there.
Wow, you're not gonna
believe this.
Hospital in Carson Springs
just called CBI.
Someone left a baby girl with a birthmark
on her arm in the waiting room.
Now, if you two want to see her,
you better come with us
'cause they're gonna let you
anywhere near her otherwise.
And if it is Caitlyn,
she's evidence.
- Okay?
- Why would he come?
I'm her father.
- Just...
- And a fine one you are.
- You step back, old man!
- Okay!
- Will you try me?
- If you want what's best for Caitlyn
you need to call a truce.
Let's go.
Which hospital is it?
- There's more than one?
- There's three.
She, uh... she didn't
say which one.
Let's find out what...
Van Pelt?
Oh, damn it! My phone
just ran out of charge.
- Can you call her?
- No. My phone is in the car.
Miriam, can I borrow your phone
just for one second?
Thank you.
- Van Pelt?
- Okay, I'm ready.
Yeah, which hospital is it?
Apparently there are three, which,
"is kind of odd, considering
it's such a small place."
Okay. I'm tracking the last number
she dialed.
Got it.
- St. Vincent's. Thank you.
- What are you looking at?
I'm looking at a big,
tall, dirty peasant.
- What are you looking at?
- You know, I already warned you two.
- A dead man.
- Yeah, I told you...
- Let's go.
- Yeah, let's go.
Um, here. Thank you
for the use of your phone.
- Let's get out of here.
- We'll be in touch. Goodbye.
Listen. I hate to mess
with you, but, uh...
I was lying again.
No Caitlyn.
But we'll have her very soon.
I promise.
And... And...
and we'll be in touch.
Okay?
Thank you, Grace.
15009 Ashley Ridge drive.
- Told you it'd work.
- Hasn't worked yet.
She has to figure out
what we're up to.
At this very moment, she's probably
calling whoever has the baby
and telling them
to get the hell out of there.
How's she gonna warn them?
Her phone's dead.
She could use the landline.
I bet she doesn't know
the number.
I mean, no one knows
numbers these days.
You just have them programmed
into your phone.
Hello.
Uh... yes?
Hi.
- Where's Ruth?
- She's under arrest.
She didn't know what I did.
She thought she was just taking care
of a child in a custody dispute.
So she said.
How did you know?
The diapers and the milk
were taken from the motel room
which told me that Red John's
partner was someone frugal.
Very organized, meticulous.
Someone who would take care
of the baby.
Probably a woman.
Middle age.
Wanting a child.
I told Eileen that Caitlyn
would be taken away
by social services if she didn't completely
separate herself from Roddy.
She was devastated,
but she did it.
She moved to the motel.
Easy pickings.
You did all this for a child?
Have you heard of adoption?
Well, sure. But this way
I could help Red John also.
And Caitlyn's such a lovely girl.
Always happy and smiling.
- Tell me about Red John.
- He's been a good friend to me.
- For how long?
- A long time. A long time.
- Why did he kill Eileen?
- I don't know.
You don't ask him questions.
But it had to be her.
It was important to him
that it was her.
He told me this might happen,
and if it did
that I should give you something.
- Easy.
- It's okay.
I mean you no harm.
- What is it?
- I'm done talking.
"Something's gotten hold
of my heart"
"keeping my soul
and my senses apart"
"Something's gotten
into my life"
"cutting its way through
my dreams like a knife"
"Turning me up"
"and turning me down"
"Making me smile"
"and making me frown"
What's on the disc?
"Hello, Patrick."
"As you can see,
things didn't go as I planned."
"Don't say I told you so."
"Red John wants me
to read a message to you"
"and in return, he won't
make me suffer so much."
"He was really mad at me"
"so I think this is very fair
under the circumstances."
"Patrick"
"Lorelei told me what she told you
about shaking my hand."
"So I know that you've
made a list"
"and I know that by the time
you watch this video"
"you'll have narrowed
that list down to a few names."
"That's quite a feat
of memory and research."
"Bravo."
"I bet you think
you're pretty damn clever"
"but you're not."
"You got a lucky break.
That's not clever."
"I'll show you clever."
"I'm going to kill a happy memory
that you've never told anyone."
"And when you investigate"
"I'm going to lead you
right to this video."
"There's more."
"Right now, I want you
to take out"
"your list of suspects
and look at the names."
"I'll give you a moment."
"Okay."
"The names are..."
"Bret Stiles..."
"Gale Bertram..."
"Raymond Haffner..."
"Reede Smith..."
"Bob Kirkland..."
"Sheriff Thomas McAllister..."
"Brett Partridge."
"There. See?
That's clever."
"But fair's fair, Patrick."
"You've changed the game,
so there's new rules now."
"Eileen Turner
is the first of many."
"I'm going to start
killing again. Often."
"Until you catch me..."
"or I catch you."